Yuvraj Soni.

Web Developer & Designer.

yuvrajsoni92@gmail.com

Summary

Hello, my name is Yuvraj. I am a Web Expert living in rajasthan, india. Experienced in web designing & developing. Several years of experience in wide range of design disciplines focusing on user interaction and user experience. Currently working as a Entry Level Freelancer Web Developer & Web designer. In the spring 2013, during my first year of college at MISU University Udaipur (Raj.) India. I took a general PHP course where we were assigned the task of building a webpage in Word. Thus began my love affair with coding & designing.

UI/UX DESIGN:-

UI/UX involves planning and iterating a site's structure and layout. Once the proper information architecture is in place, I design the visual layer to create a beautiful user experience.

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT:-

Front End Development is building out the visual components of a website. Using HTML, CSS, and Javascript, I build fast, interactive websites. This also may include integrating a CMS.

Code:-

I design in the browser with HTML(5), CSS(3) and a touch of JavaScript. I love coding things from scratch, but I can work with front-end frameworks like Bootstrap too.

Ideas:-

I collaborate with clients and peers to nurture and transform ideas into well thought out design specs. After all, that's where the majority of amazing user experiences start.

Experience

Web Developer at Freelancer (Entry Level).

HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, SQL.

January 2015 - Present.

Head Enginner at iBall Solution.

January 2012 - June 2017. (5 years 6 months)

Education

RVD University, Udaipur (Raj).

Master's Degree, MCA, 2016 - 2018.

Mohanlal Sukhadia University, Udaipur (Raj).

Bachelor's Degree, BCA, 2013 - 2016.